

Summarv

I focus on crafting the most stable, secure and efficient UNIX or UNIX-like experience possible. My passion for technology, coupled with commitment to excellence drives me to continuously explore innovative solutions, enhancing the capabilities and ensuring that the infrastructure of the team I work in remains at the forefront of technological advancements. Acquiring new skills comes naturally to me, as I am a quick learner. My ability to grasp concepts rapidly, coupled with my intuition, allows me to adapt and learn effectively on the go.

Profiles

in datcuandrei

datcuandrei

Education

"Ferdinand I" Curtea de Arges

Electronics and Automation 8.49

2017 - 2021

High School

Certifications

PostgreSQL Fundamentals

Programming Hub

February 2023

Link to certificate

Credential ID: 1675272172380

Docker Certification

Programming Hub

January 2023

Link to certificate

Credential ID: 1674304167752

Linux Certification

Programming Hub January 2023

Link to certificate

Credential ID: 1674045915215

Andrei Datcu

DevOps Engineer

- ⊗ Sibiu, Romania & +40736937468 @ datcu.andrei.2@protonmail.com •

Experience

Scriptics Decisions

DevOps Engineer

February 2023 - Present Sibiu, Romania

Website

Maintaning and deploying services on a large scale of servers:

- Deployed Nagios Core as monitoring system for all servers
- Migrated GNU/Linux (Ubuntu Server & CentOS) servers to our infrastructure for large scale businesses
- Migrated numerous websites using different CMS: Wordpress, TYPO3, WHM cPanel, etc.
- Experience with NGINX and Apache Web Server; hardened NGINX and Apache for security, reverse proxies, etc.
- Migrated hypervisors running Proxmox VE Maintaining servers for businesses
- Configuration and usage of hypervisors that run Proxmox VE
- Automated backup solution using Proxmox BS
- Created numerous scripts for maintenance and automated tasks.
- Migrated DBs using MySQL and MariaDB
- Implemented a security assistant (Greenbone) in our infrastructure to scan vulnerabilities.
- Implemented Grafana in our infrastructure, and PNP4Nagios to get graphs for our monitoring system
- Written Ansible Playbooks in order to automatically deploy Nagios Core using our configurations
- Created Nagios NRPE Plugin alternative that doesnt use SSL
- Implemented Docker Swarms with Traefik as a load balancer and other custom scripts for deployment and synchronization for zero downtime.
- Automated Proxmox VE Backup extraction to retrieve certain data through mounting the QEMU SCSI drives as loopback devices, rearraging the LVM. Proxmox VE uses proprietary standards such as VMA and ZST.
- Automated Proxmox BS Backup extraction through Proxmox BS API, as our backups use indexes for incrementing over last backup.
- Migrated infrastructure to and from client's AWS. Continuous maintenance.
- Automated security and uptime reports for clients written in Python using Greenbone's and UptimeRobot's API

Continental AG

IT Operations Intern

July 2023 - October 2023 Sibiu, Romania

Key responsibilities:

- System deployment: Install debug and configure operating systems (Windows and Linux) on various laptops, desktops or virtual machines
- Software deployment: Install debug and configure different software across the environment.
- Provide Technical support and Incident Management.
- Hardware issues: Debug and fix different hardware issues within the clients devices(laptops, desktops, ...etc.)
- Scripting and programing: Basic scripting and automation tasks (Powershell, Bash. C#...etc.)

TAEGSM

July 2016 - June 2020

GSM/IT Technician Curtea de Arges

Key responsabilities:

- Troubleshooting phones, tablets, consoles, but mostly PCs and laptops
- Installing and debugging software on various hardware and VMs.
- Installing and configuring a wide-range of OS (Windows, macOS, Linux)
- Flashing firmwares on mobile devices using the manufacturer's tools or thirdparty solutions
- Modifying the firmware (e.g. unlocking bootloaders, unlocking the region locks for certain SIM carriers, etc.)
- Debugging and fixing diverse hardware issues on a wide range of devices.